太空堡垒卡拉狄加 【 前情提要 】
HELO: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
我们都做出了牺牲
We all made sacrifices.
是吗?        对
Is that so? Yes, that's right.
那为什么有个赛昂情人 在占着我的职位?
Then how come some Cylon lover is holding down my post?
赫拉还活着 我是她的母亲 我要去找她
ATHENA: Hera's alive. I'm her mother and I'm going to get her.
我求你了
I'm begging you to do this.
你是在以整个舰队冒险 你知道吗?
You've put the entire fleet in jeopardy. Are you aware of that?
我不是叛徒 我做的是我认为正确的事
I'm not a traitor. I did what I thought was right.
她会找到赫拉的
She'll get Hera.
走
Let's go.
别开枪
No! Hold your fire!
让开
Get out of the way!
把那东西关禁闭
Throw that thing in the brig.
作为殖民地公民
I demand my rights as a Colonial citizen
我有权要求法律代表出庭 以及完整的法定诉讼程序
to legal representation and full due process.
是吗?
Do you?
那下一步怎么办?        让他得到公正的审判
So what happens next? We give him his trial.
右舷机库真能挤下那么多平民吗?
Do they really think they can squeeze most of these onto the starboard hangar deck?
所以才调西洛来…
That's why Helo was transferred down here,
管理这些难民的
to manage the civilian refugees.
长官 尊者号乘客登舰 现场混乱
Sir, we got the breakdown on the Thera Sita's inhabitants coming aboard.
51名撒纪特恩人        老天爷
Fifty-one Sagittarons. Oh, boy.
西洛可能应付不过来
Helo might be overmatched down there.
昨晚没怎么睡吧?
So, pretty rough night last night, huh?
你昨晚睡得不太好
Hey, I said you didn't sleep so well.
做的梦让人烦
Just a stupid dream. Whatever.
那你没事?        恩
So, you're okay? Yeah.
他们还会送来300人 你能顶得住?
They're about to increase the population down there by 300 and you're okay.
能 我不知道该把他们安排到哪里
Yeah. I don't know where I'm gonna put them,
可我又不是不了解我自己 没事的
but it's not like I'm walking around taking my own pulse. I'm fine.
他在那边    这不是道格维尔的市长么
APOLLO: Hey. There he is. STARBUCK: If it isn't the Mayor of Dogsville.
放他一马吧  兄弟们
RACETRACK: Hey. Cut him some slack, guys.
听说你刚收到一整船忠诚子民
Helo just got a new shipload of loyal subjects.
帮我个忙
Helo, come here, come here. Listen, I need a favor.
今晚我和一位有型的菜鸟帅哥
I have a date tonight with this ripped and ready nugget
想把关系拉进一步
that I want to break in, you know, just right.
能在下面 给我安排个
Think you can wrangle me up
甜蜜的小寝室不?
one of those cute little sexy cubicles you got down there?
好  好啦        回见  西洛
Yeah, yeah. APOLLO: We'll see you around, Helo.
你们知道到哪可以找到我
Yeah. You guys know where to find me.
你会去看赫拉吧?        会的  宝贝 我会去看她
You're gonna check up on Hera, right? Yes. Babe, I'm gonna check up on Hera.
我爱你    我也爱你
Okay. Love you. Love you, too.
继续走 继续走
HELO: I need you to keep moving. You need to keep moving.
等到了就会处理
Deal with you when we get there.
我们会处理好的 拜托
I know, I know. We'll deal with your concerns. Come on.
继续走 继续走
You just keep moving. Keep moving.
各位  欢迎登上卡拉狄加  我是卡尔・阿格森上尉
Welcome aboard Galactica, people. My name is Captain Karl Agathon.
我被派来处理各位的福利问题
I've been assigned to look after your personal welfare.
我们很快就会办理  各位先继续向前走
We'll get to it soon. I need you to keep moving right now.
你们把撒纪特恩人安排在哪里?
Where are you putting the Sagittarons?
住宿安排还没有定下来 先生
Living arrangements haven't been made yet, sir.
继续向前走    我们要和自己人在一起
I need you to keep moving. We want to be with our own!
你听到他说的话了 快走
You heard the man. Get your ass in motion!
走!
Move!
一切都在我的控制之下  上校
I got things under control here, Colonel.
恩  是的
Yeah. Sure you do.
打扰下  女士 我能大致检查一下你的儿子吗?
Excuse me, ma'am? Could I have a brief look at your son?
不用了  我们很好  我们没事  不用看医生
No, no, no. We're fine. We're fine. We don't need a doctor.
知道 谢谢
I know. I know. Thank you.
我们不用看医生
Look. We don't need a doctor.
我们是撒纪特恩人 我们不相信药物
We're Sagittaron. We don't believe in medicine.
没事的  女士  这位是罗伯特医生  他是民间医生
It's all right, ma'am. This is Dr. Robert. He's our civilian doctor.
与军方没有关联
He has nothing to do with the military.
相信我 我们会尊重你们的传统
He'll respect your traditions. You can trust me.
我也是撒纪特恩人 不会有事的
I'm a Sagittaron. It's okay.
没事的 可以了?
It's okay. Okay? Okay?
疼吗?
You feel that?
请把嘴张开  好吗?  张大一些
Would you open your mouth for me, please? Open wide.
好
All right.
看这个
Look at this.
有什么感觉吗?  这里呢?
Okay. Do you feel anything? How about here?
好了  够了 谢谢
All right. That's enough. Thank you.
把你的手拿开!        好
Get your hands off me! ROBERT: All right, okay.
再等一下    够了
Just a second... That's enough. That's enough.
谢谢
Thank you very much. Settle down.
先生   把你的手管好
Sir... Hey, you just keep your hands to yourself.
好  好的
Okay. Yeah. All right?
麦克
TIGH: Mike.
你个出老千的笨蛋 还欠我一杯酒钱
You brain-dead card cheat. Still owe me that drink.
少 闪一边去    今天你心情不错哇
Saul, get out of here now. Well, you're in a good mood today.
医生  我说不准  可这里有些人看来…
Hey, Doc. I don't know, but some of these people, they look...
有病 有病 对
Sick. Sick. Yeah.
急救员!
My God! Medic!
罗伯特医生?        离开这里  少
DUALLA: Dr. Robert! Leave, Saul.
好
Yeah.
别碰我的儿子
No, get your hands off my son!
好了        别碰  别碰
I got him. No. No!
他们要把他带到哪里去?
Where are they taking him?
没事  女士 这边走
It's all right, ma'am. Just walk this way.
什么情况  麦克?
So what have we got here, Mike?
梅罗莱克病
Mellorak Sickness.
它源于肾脏
It originates in the kidneys
而后迅速扩展到呼吸及免疫系统
and then rapidly attacks the respiratory and the immune system.
这种病比较让人头疼
It's a nasty bit of business.
如果首发症状无法在48小时内得到医治
If you don't treat the first symptoms within 48 hours,
患者将在三到五天内死亡
it'll kill you within three to five days.
传染性如何?
How contagious is it?
不是空气传播 所以我们也算是走运
Well, it's not airborne, so we lucked out there.
它通过人与人之间接触传染
It's spread through human contact,
唾液  性交 皮肤接触
saliva, sexual intercourse, through the skin...
目前看来 这种病还仅限于撒纪特恩人之中
Right now, it seems confined to the Sagittarons.
那就好 不用他们道谢了
That's good. They're welcome to it.
传播地点显然正是我们工作的地方
It's obviously spreading down there where we were working.
可治愈吗?        绝对可以
It's curable? Absolutely, yes.
打一针贝他霉素 患者在一两天内就生龙活虎了
A shot of bittamusin and you're right as rain in a day or two.
镇静剂也可以缓解病情
And sedatives alleviate the symptoms.
但我不知道我们的贝他霉素库存量能坚持多久
But I don't know how long our stock of bittamusin will hold out,
所以我们应该先存起来
so we should probably conserve it
等首发症状出现后 再用作预防注射
and only inoculate after the first symptoms show.
这是民间传染病  罗伯特医生  所以应该由你来负责
ADAMA: This is a civilian infection, Dr. Robert, so it's in your hands.
不过蒂罗尔和其他船员 必须接种疫苗以防生病
But I want Tyrol and the crew immunized before they get sick.
不能有丝毫懈怠
I don't need any downtime.
如果消毒后加强卫生 有些人就不会得病了
If we disinfect everything and stress hygiene, some people won't get sick.
他们也就不需要药品
And they won't need the medicine.
应该让每人都冲澡吧?
Then shouldn't we get everyone to the showers?
尤其是撒纪特恩人 我们应该发出通知
Especially the Sagittarons. We should make an announcement.
到此地步  我们不能再孤立他们了
No. No, we don't want to single them out any more than we already have to.
否则就会引发骚乱
We'll have a riot on our hands.
要我说 就先安排好撒纪特恩人
Now, if it were up to me, I would say just get the Sagittarons settled
然后再处理其他民众
and then deal with the civvies that have already arrived.
至少用不着担心给撒纪特恩人的药品会不够用
Well, at least, you won't have to worry about having enough medicine for the Sagittarons.
对   他们中大部分人都会拒绝使用
Yeah. Most of them are gonna refuse it.
有人会因此而死掉
People are going to die.
3000年以来 药物一直被认作是不详之物
For the last 3,000 years, medicine's been the great curse.
那是因为他们 是一群食古不化  专吃树根的蠢货
That's because they're a bunch of stubborn root-sucking jackasses
只会守着千年的传统不放
holding onto traditions that are 1,000 years old.
喝吧
Drink this.
够臭吧?        恩  确实刺鼻
Stink enough for you in here? Yeah, it's a really potent smell, yeah.
牛蒡根 撒纪特恩人用它来做镇静剂
That's burdock root. The Sagittarons use it as a calmative.
有效吗?
Does it work?
哼  不知道  反正他们都难逃一死
Hell, I don't know. They're all gonna die anyway.
审判不是真的吧
ZAREK: Tell me there won't be a trial.
盖尤斯・波塔尔 将因重罪和叛国罪而受到审判
Gaius Baltar will be tried for high crimes and treason.
仲裁庭的法官将会听取指证他的证据
A tribunal of judges will hear the evidence against him.
将宣判对他的裁决 他会被判为有罪
A verdict will be read. He will be found guilty
他最终会为他的行为负责
and he will be finally held responsible for his actions.
如果你可以同我一样有些耐心
If you can summon up a little patience, as I have done,
我们就会经受住这次考验
we will get through this ordeal.
听我说 波塔尔会受到审判
Listen to me. Baltar will get his trial.
而你得到的将会是一场飓风 (译注:暗指来势凶猛的考验)
And this is what you'll get, a hurricane.
媒体将会如期而至
The media will descend on you
密切监视 质问你的一举一动
and watch and scrutinize and question your every move.
教派冲突
You will have sectarian violence.
刺杀行动
You will have assassination attempts.
还有你从没见过的大规模内乱
You will have civil unrest on a scale we've never seen.
工作  劳动 这支舰队的每项日常工作都将停止
Work, labor, everyday routine in this fleet will come to a complete halt.
这场审判将会使整个舰队走向灭亡
This trial is going to bring this entire fleet down.
副总统阁下 我们有相应的安全计划
Mr. Vice President, we have a security plan in order,
包括迅速布置陆战队
which includes rapid marine deployment,
增加空中巡逻行动  安全卫士
increased CAP operations, security details...
一场飓风  劳拉
A hurricane, Laura.
换作是我 在审判期间 我会宣布戒严法
If I were you, I'd declare martial law during the trial.
要活下来 光有耐心是不够的
You're going to need a lot more than a little patience to survive.
有事叫我
I'm here if you need me.
至友至敌
Your best friend, your worst enemy.
我从没看过他这个样子
I've never seen him like that.
他真的害怕了
He was truly frightened.
我们没病
MAN: We are not sick.
是狗撒把病带来的 把他们赶回去!
Sagits brought the sickness with them. Send them back!
好  先生 你说我把他们赶到哪里去?
Okay, sir. Where do you suggest that I send them?
不知道 你们自己想办法
I don't know. Figure it out.
好 我们已经了解你们的问题了 我们会尽力而为
Okay. Your concerns have been noted. We're going to do the best we can.
算了吧  鬼才信
Yeah, right you will.
有什么事可以为您效劳吗?
Yes. Can I help you?
我儿子死了
My son is dead.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
那是"胴穗"吧?
It's a soma braid, right?
你们撒纪特恩人以为它能带来安康?
You Sagittarons believe it's supposed to bring good health?
抱歉 仅限于此是不够的
Look, I'm sorry. It's not enough.
如果你不治疗  这病是会出人命的
If you don't treat the disease, it's fatal, okay?
这本不该发生
This... This didn't have to happen.
不  这是必然的  他是被别人害死的
Yes, it did. He was killed.
不是 女士 他是病死的 他的死是因为他本需要的是真正的药品
No. Ma'am, he died. Okay? He died because he needed real medicine.
他的死 是因为我犯了一个错误
He died because I made a mistake.
对
Okay.
好  对  请让大家都知道
Okay. Good. Yeah. Then, please, tell the others.
我会的 我会告诉他们不要相信他
I will. I will tell them not to trust him.
他们警告过我要提防他 但我没听
They warned me about him, but I wouldn't listen.
我不想让我儿子死掉
I didn't want my son to die.
我挺而走险 去找罗伯特医生
I took a chance. I went to Dr. Robert.
我让那医生给威利用了药
I let the doctor give the medicine to Willie.
女士 你耽搁得太久了
Ma'am, you waited too long.
威利生病前后不到12小时
Willie had been sick for less than 12 hours.
他才19岁  就这么死了
He was 19. He is dead.
是那医生害死了我的儿子
That doctor killed my son.
昨晚又死一个人
We lost another one last night.
对  威利・金
Yeah. Willie King.
不是 一个三岁的小女孩 她的父母拒绝让我治疗她
No. A three-year-old girl whose parents refused to let me treat her.
威利・金的母亲失去了威利・金
Willie King's mother lost Willie King.
他的死真可惜 他来的时候你也看到了
It's a shame. That boy was a goner. You saw him when he came in here.
出现症状的三天后才来
I mean, he was at least three days symptomatic.
这事你和他母亲解释过了?        是的  那是当然
You explained this to the mother? Yes. Of course I did.
我能和她怎么说?
I mean, what the hell am I supposed to say to her?
我很遗憾  女士  但如果你能
"Sorry, ma'am, but if you would have just turned the corner a little sooner
早些放弃那些迷信思想  你的儿子可能就有救了?
"on your superstitious crap, we could have saved your son"?
把你的衬衫脱掉  好吗?        什么?
Get your shirt off, would you? Excuse me?
我要给你打疫苗
I'm going to vaccinate you.
可我没有病  我们不是在限量供应么
But I'm not sick. I thought we were rationing.
你以为我要看到你躺在床上以后才来治你吗?
You think I'm gonna wait until you're on your back for a day?
那样谁来帮我?
Who the hell else is gonna help me around here?
好  那好吧
Okay. All right.
我和泰聊过 他问我关于你的事
I talked to Tigh. He was asking about you.
我告诉他你工作很出色
I told him you were doing a hell of a job.
找不到第二个合适的人选
I mean, I wouldn't wish this place on anybody.
来  准备好了?        恩
Come on. You ready? Yeah.
可能会有点疼 好了
This might sting a bit. You're done.
嗯
Yes!
好了  "僵尸手"
Awesome! All right, "Hands of Stone. "
让我看看你有什么能耐    玛吉  要投中哦
Let me see what you got. CONNOR: Put it in the hole, Marge.
想知道我的秘诀是什么吗  康纳?  我把球洞当作是你的脸
Want to know my secret, Connor? I pretend this thing is your face.
是梅罗莱克(病)大侠  大家快闪呐
Hey. It's Mellorak Man. Everybody run.
别紧张 医生给我打过预防针了
Relax. The doc dosed me.
听说下面挺惨烈的 除非你是撒纪特恩人
I hear it's pretty rough down there, huh? Only if you're a Sagittaron.
那些垂死的人看起来好傻
Dying, you know? It just... It just seems so senseless.
我是不会掉眼泪的
Yeah, well, you'll get no tears from me.
我的兄弟们还要在他们的恶臭中 挥汗如雨就已经够烦的了
Bad enough my gang's gotta sweat through their stench.
我有预感 等到有一天药品不够用的时候
I have a feeling, one of these days, we're gonna wake up in the morning,
我会很恼火
I'm gonna be really pissed 'cause we're out of meds
就因为那些混球开窍了 我们要和他们分享药品
'cause those frakwads saw the light and now we gotta share.
你要唠叨个没完 还是投球?
Will you babble or shoot?
好!
Yeah!
那些宗教怪胎
None of those religious
在新卡布里卡上打赛昂人的时候没出一点力
freaks lifted a finger down on New Caprica against the Cylons.
轮机长  算了吧
Hey. Chief, knock it off.
许多抵抗军战士英勇牺牲
Well, a lot of good Resistance people lost their lives.
我说过别再说了
I said knock it off. All right?
哦
Oh.
不好意思  小杜    没事
Sorry, Dee. It's all right.
我比你们更有理由 生他们的气  我本身就是撒纪特恩人
I have more of a reason to be mad at them than you do. I am Sagittaron.
他们中大部分人疑神疑鬼 愚蠢顽固  争强斗狠
Most of them are paranoid, pigheaded and argumentative.
他们确实把罗伯特医生弄得惨兮兮的
Yeah, well, they're sure making it miserable for Dr. Robert.
药物是令人憎恶的东西  是有违神旨的罪过
Medicine's an abomination. It's a sin against the Gods.
医生在散布疾病 因为他们拒绝承认身体…
Physicians are spreading disease because they refuse to acknowledge that the body...
进了
APOLLO: There you go.
和心灵是神话的产物    这副身体不是神秘之物
...and the mind are myths. Well, this body is no myth.
如果我病了 我就去找罗伯特医生    你不会生病的
If I get sick, I'm gonna see Dr. Robert. You're not getting sick.
除了科特尔谁都可以
Anyone but Cottle.
那个四眼混蛋说不定会拿长钉代替针头
The near-sighted bastard might as well use a spike instead of a needle.
那他们对你还挺好的?    恩  还好
So, they're treating you well, then? Yeah. Well enough.
他们要花些时间才会切入正题  不是么?
Take a while to get to the point, though, don't they?
六号 谢谢你能这么做
Look, Six, I want to thank you for what you did.
虽然我还不清楚你这么做的原因
I'm still not sure why you did it, though.
确实如此
Exactly.
我们来这里干什么?
What are we doing here?
你怎么可以对这些人动了恻隐之心?
How could you possibly throw yourself on the mercy of these people?
可你却落得这份境遇  恩
ATHENA: And now you're here. Yeah.
如果你想保住性命 只能和他们合作
Your best chance of survival is to work with them.
就是说要帮他们把波塔尔的罪行昭之天下
And that means to help them expose Baltar for his crimes.
我得走了
Look, I gotta go,
我会为你找些衣服
so I'm gonna look into getting some clothes for you.
照顾好自己
Please, take care of yourself.
嗨
Hey.
谢谢你来看我
Thank you for the visit.
能让我有个伴 谢谢
To have some company. Thank you.
恩  我担心你
ATHENA: No. I care about you.
你以为他们中的每个人都担心你?
BALTAR: Do you think any of them care about you?
我可没那么想
I imagine they don't.
那你为什么还要来这里?
So what are you doing here again?
我还在考虑这个问题
I'm still trying to figure that out.
你是来救他的吧?
So you're here to save him, are you?
我说过了我不知道
I told you, I don't know.
你之所以来这里是因为你想成为人类
You're here because you want to be human.
要成为人类可有个窍门
There's a trick to being human.
你必须只求自保
You have to think only about yourself.
你说她现在又是在做什么?    不知道
ROSLIN: Okay. What do you think she's doing now? I don't know.
像是在自言自语或是和某人说话
Though she's talking to something or someone, I don't know.
我以前也看到过她这个样子
I've seen her do it before.
他要害死我    退后
MAN: He'll kill me! Stay back!
够了
Enough!
他要杀了我们
WOMAN: He'll frakking kill us!
不能让他这么做了 他是凶手    不！
MAN 2: You can't let him do it! He's a murderer! MAN 3: No!
后退!
Stand back!
别碰我  抓住他
MAN 4: Get off me! MAN 5: Get him!
后退
Stay back!
都散开！
GUARD: Break it up!
放开我!
Get off me!
后退 都后退    离他远点!
MAN 6: Stay back! Everybody back! MAN 7: Step away from him!
都后退
Everybody back!
放开他  都后退
Get off him! Now! Move back, people!
后退 立即后退
Move back! Back away, now!
他害死了我父亲
He killed my father!
我想救他 你个愚昧的笨蛋!
I tried to help him, you ignorant fool!
放开我!
Get off me!
到我后面去
Okay. Get behind me.
都后退
GUARD: Back down, everybody.
你给那位大爷打了预防针 可他还是死了?
So you immunized the old man, but he still died.
巴克明斯特和他父亲同是原教派
Buckminster and his father are fundamentalists.
为什么他们改变了主意来打预防针?
What made them change their mind about getting immunized?
"他们改变了主意"?  谁说他们改变了主意?
Change their mind? Who said they changed their mind?
我亲自给他注射的贝他霉素    未经他们同意?
I administered the bittamusin on my own. Without their consent?
当时是深夜
Look, it was the middle of the night.
我在巡诊  那老头疼得直叫
I was doing my rounds and the old man was screaming in pain.
你说我能怎么办?
I mean, what was I supposed to do?
我不明白 我们不是在限量供应吗?
Okay, I don't understand. Aren't we rationing?
48小时后  就回天乏术了
It was well after the 48 hours.
话是没错  但也不准确  人和人不同
Yeah, that's right. But it's not exact. Everybody's different.
好吧  我承认 他已经奄奄一息了
Okay. He was marginal.
我不会坐在这里  为我的尽职尽责而向你道歉
Look, I'm not gonna sit here and apologize to you for doing my job.
那边还有两个派亢人  他们已经开始出现该症状了
Now I got two Picons down there that are starting to show symptoms.
如果你不介意 我要去看一下他们的病情
Now I'm gonna go treat them, if it's all right with you.
医生给他用药的时间
The doctor's version of when he administered the drug
与给金女士的相比有很大的出入
greatly differed from that of Mrs. King.
谁?        那个女人  金
Who? The woman. King.
我与您说过的  金女士  她的儿子在出现了症状后
The one I told you about. Mrs. King. Her son showed symptoms.
她马上带他去罗伯特那里医治  但那孩子还是死了
She immediately took him to Robert for treatment. The boy still died.
另一件病例中
In the other case,
罗伯特在未经那个撒纪特恩人许可的情况下就治疗他
Robert treated a Sagittaron without the man's consent.
我们从一开始 就不应该对他们这样
That's something we probably should have done to all of them in the first place.
不然这里早就没有这种病了
This disease would have been gone by now.
我们之所以没这么做
The only reason we didn't
是因为尊重撒纪特恩人的风俗
is we're trying to respect the customs of the Sagittarons.
说的就是这点 他并没尊重他们的风俗
But that's the point. He didn't respect them, sir.
经过罗伯特医治的人 可能会死掉
People could be dying under Robert's care.
每天经过我医治的人也会死掉 这该死的差事就是这样
People die under my care every day. It goes with the damn job.
害人不算在内    "害人"?
Killing doesn't. Killing?
你这可就太过分了
You are way out of line.
麦克・罗伯特 可不应当受到这种对待
Mike Robert deserves better than this.
就算是我弄错了 就算他没对这些人做出什么 有损医德的事
Even if I'm wrong, even if he isn't treating some of these people unethically,
我担心 他还是造成了一定影响
I'm concerned he's created a situation down there.
不好的影响
It's bad.
上尉
Captain,
我这里有一位锒铛入狱的前殖民地总统
I have the former President of the Colonies sitting in a prison cell,
一个被监禁的赛昂女人
a Cylon woman is in custody,
还有一群恨不得将他们五马分尸的民众
and a population that would love nothing more than to tear both of them apart.
我的战舰上人满为患  手头上又出现了传染病
My ship is overcrowded and I have an epidemic on my hands.
现在的问题是你是否能胜任这份工作?
Now the question is are you capable of doing your job?
是否能停止这些无根无据的指控?
And are you gonna stop making these unfounded accusations?
能吗?
Are you?
能  长官        解散
Yes, sir. Dismissed.
阿格森!
TIGH: Agathon!
就此罢手吧  西洛
Why don't you knock it off, Helo?
别吃饱了撑的再找医生的麻烦了 这么做对你没好处
Get your teeth out of the doc's ass. It's not doing you any good.
恕我直言  长官  我认为麦克・罗伯特可能在害人
With all due respect, sir, I think Michael Robert might be hurting people.
据我所知 他是唯一一个…
He is the only one who's had anything good to say about you
说你好话的人
in as long as I can remember.
你把你仅存的一点可信度
You may as well take whatever credibility you have left
也拱手送了出去
and chuck it out an airlock.
你真要替这些疯子出头?
You seriously want to stand up for these crazy frakking people?
你哪根筋不对了?
What is it with you?
你就是喜欢隔岸观火  对吧?
You just like being on the outside looking in, don't you?
我太不明白 你这句话是什么意思
I don't quite know what you mean by that, sir.
除非你是在说我的妻子 旧事重提?
Unless you're referring to my wife. Again.
麦克・罗伯特是顶天立地的汉子
Mike Robert is a stand-up guy.
卡布里卡人  自己人 我信赖的人
A Caprican. One of our own. A man I can trust.
在新卡布里卡 他与抵抗军共同作战
On New Caprica, he worked with the Resistance.
他修补了我的眼睛 他与敌人作斗争
He patched up my eye. He fought the enemy,
而你这时候正和你那赛昂老婆在被窝里亲亲我我
while you were snuggled up in bed with your Cylon wife every night...
上校!
GUARD: Colonel!
还好吧?
You okay?
你他妈还是很在意你的朋友们的想法的?
So you do give a frak what your friends think.
很好 就该这样
Good for you. That's how it should be.
但你要知道 我他妈也在乎
But you know what? I give a frak, too.
我也在乎朋友  在乎对朋友的忠诚
About friends, about loyalty.
你再去败坏老麦的名声  我就和你没完
You keep soiling Mike Robert's good name and we are gonna finish this.
怎么样?
How does that sound to you?
去让医生看一下你的手吧
Better have the doctor take a look at that hand, huh?
抱歉  你要先等等
HELO: Sorry, people, you're gonna have to wait.
借过  借过
Excuse me. Excuse me.
15分钟  各位  我在15分钟后回来  抱歉
Fifteen minutes, people. I'll be back in 15 minutes. I'm sorry.
借过  借过  先生  把手拿开
Excuse me. Excuse me. Sir, get your hands off me.
莎伦    西洛
Sharon? Helo!
出什么事了?  赫拉怎么样了?
What's going on? How's Hera?
什么意思?
What do you mean, "How's Hera?"
她在大约一小时前生病了 他们把我从巡逻任务中换了下来
She got sick about an hour ago. They pulled me off CAP.
什么意思? 没人告诉我啊
What are you talking about? No one told me.
他们把她送到罗伯特医生那里了
They sent her to Dr. Robert.
我还没考虑好  她是否真的需要打针
Okay. You know what? I don't know if she needs this.
这是大事  她会死的
Hey, this is serious. She could die from this.
好了  来吧  没事  没事  看这个
All right, here we go. Here we go. Okay. It's all right. Look at this.
看这个 你的玩具在这里
Look at this. Here. Here's your toy.
好孩子  好孩子
Good girl. Good girl.
这些是口服镇静剂
Now, these are a sedative in pill form. Okay.
每六小时一片 压碎后服用
Just give her a half every six hours. Just crush it up.
好的
Okay. Okay?
她应该没什么事吧?    没事的 你可以带她回家了
She'll be okay, though? She'll be fine. You can take her home.
谢谢你  医生
Thank you, Doctor. Okay.
拜拜
Bye-bye. Say bye.
好  拜拜
Good night. Bye-bye.
我们要走了  快说拜拜
ATHENA: Good, we're done. Say bye-bye.
拜拜
Bye-bye.
她不会有事的
She'll be fine. All right?
知道了吧?
Okay.
好
Oh, um...
帮我把这个给金女士好吗?    这是…
Listen, would you give this to Mrs. King? This is...
她儿子的 应该还给她
It belonged to her son. I know she'd want it back.
好吗?
All right?
你好
Hi.
罗伯特医生让我把这个还给你
Dr. Robert gave me this to give to you.
这是他给你的?
He gave you this?
你的女儿怎么样了?
How is your daughter?
挺好的  谢谢        那就好
She's fine, thanks. Good.
金女士 请留步
Mrs. King? Please.
我要问你一些事
I need to ask you something.
如果你认为罗伯特医生是个危险人物 为什么要让他给你儿子看病
If you thought Dr. Robert was dangerous, why let him treat your son?
你说过已经有人警告过你了
I mean, you said you were warned.
我无法相信一个人的心里能藏有那么大仇恨
I couldn't believe anyone could have that much hate inside of them.
可你也知道...        我要说的话已经说完了
But you understand how... I'm through talking.
就算再说 威利也不会活过来了
Talking isn't going to bring Willie back.
我看你应该离开了
I think you should leave now.
金女士  我…
Mrs. King, I...
抱歉
I'm sorry.
看你一副怒不可遏的样子
You seem angry.
没有  只是… 工作上的事
I'm not. I'm just... Work.
不喜欢你的工作没关系 不喜欢就直说 没关系
It's okay that you hate your job. It's okay to admit it, too.
不是工作本身的事 这个差事费力不讨好
It's not the job. I know the job sucks.
不用你说我也知道
I don't need to be reminded of it.
那好
Okay.
那是什么事?
Then what is it? Look.
我每天都能看到那些事 不想看到都不行
It's what I see every day, okay? It's hard to not see it.
看到什么事?
See what?
说话  卡尔    我不知道
Talk to me, Karl. I don't know, I keep doing it.
可总是这样 干什么事都是事与愿违
You know, I keep doing it. I keep ending up on the wrong side of everything.
可能泰说得对 可能我就想这样
You know, maybe Tigh's right. Maybe I want it that way.
如果让我做文案工作 并不因为这是我的专长
What if I'm flying a desk, not because I'm good at it,
或我是合适人选
not because I'm the right guy for the job,
而是因为众所周知 这就是…
but because it's the right punishment for the guy who crosses the line
对我所做所为的惩罚呢
and everybody knows it?
也许我就该呆在道格维尔
Maybe I belong in Dogsville.
你是说...
So, you're saying...
算了
Just leave it.
"算了"是什么意思?
What does that mean, "Just leave it"?
意思是管理这些人是你的职责所在
It means it's your job to manage these people, Helo,
你必须去做
and you just gotta do it.
恩
Yeah. You know what?
你说对了 是我自己的错
You're right. It's me.
我自己想不开
It's all in my frakking head.
我没那么说
I didn't say that.
去哪里?      不知道
Where are you going? I don't know.
医生?
Doc?
上床睡一会吧  西洛 那样还能多睡会
You ought to try a bed, Helo. You'll get more sleep that way.
他在暗害他们  这上面写得清清楚楚
He's killing them. It's right here.
你快给我出去
You get your righteous ass out of here right now,
不然我就让老头子关你禁闭 不让你出来
before I have the old man lock you up and throw away the key.
不  听我说  他在新卡布里卡上就害死了他们
No, listen to me. He killed them, on New Caprica.
看这里 这名男性来时只是咳嗽 死因却是心脏衰竭
Look. Guy goes in for a cough, he dies of heart failure.
你自己看
Here. See for yourself!
看这个 这名女性只是阑尾炎
This one. Woman had simple appendicitis.
却死在了手术台上
She died on the operating table.
他医治的派亢人 死亡率为12%
Of the Picons he treated? Twelve percent of them died.
卡布里卡人呢  他喜欢卡布里卡人  死亡率是6%
Capricans. He likes Capricans. The mortality rate was six percent.
撒纪特恩人的死亡率是90%  90%的撒纪特恩人死在了…
Sagittarons? Ninety percent. Ninety percent of the Sagittarons died...
我不会听信这些的 明白吗?
I'm not going to listen to this! You hear me?
那个人在下面忙得不可开交
That man has his hands full down there.
他针对的是撒纪特恩人 你就置之不理吗?
He's singling out Sagittarons! That doesn't bother you?
他到底…    医生  你不管吗?
What exactly... Doctor, that doesn't bother you?
他到底在干什么?        不知道 我又不是医生
What exactly is he doing? I don't know. I'm not a doctor.
这是你说的第一句清醒话
Well, now that's the first sensible thing you've said yet.
他给他们开的不是药品
Listen to me. I don't think he's giving them the medicine.
这里有鬼  他在搞鬼
Something. He's doing something!
我的天 你还真是没完没了
My Gods! You're not gonna let it go, are you?
求你 能为金女士的儿子验尸吗 看他是怎么死的
Please. Can you do an autopsy on Mrs. King's son to see how he died?
我保证  检查后 我就不管了
I'll let it go. I will. I promise. I will let it go. Just check.
我验过了 检查过金女士的儿子
I did. I checked King's son.
梅罗莱克病 他的体内有贝他霉素
Mellorak sickness. He had bittamusin in his system.
行了吗?  收手吧
All right? Now that's it.
别管这件事了 出去!
Now you just leave it. And get out of here!
医生 我觉得不太舒服
Hey, Doc? I don't really feel so good.
能给我注射一些贝他霉素吗?
Think I can get some of that bittamusin?
谁啊?
ATHENA: Who is it?
赫拉 没事
Hey, Hera. It's okay.
金女士?        你的那位军人朋友杜亚拉
Mrs. King? Your friend, the soldier, Dualla.
她生病了 她去看了医生  然后…
She's sick. She went to the doctor. She went...
慢点说  什么…      不  你听我说
Slow down, slow down. What? No, you listen to me.
今晚又有两名撒纪特恩人
We lost two more tonight,
在接受那杀人魔的治疗后死掉了
Sagittarons who let that murderer treat them.
你得想想办法
You have to do something.
她来这里干什么?
Excuse me. What is she doing here?
她在那里  女士
GUARD 1: There she is! Ma'am?
你不可以来这里  走吧  快走
You're not supposed to be here. Let's go. Now.
抱歉  上尉  他妈的难民  不知道她怎么溜进来的
Sorry, Captain. Frakking refugees. I don't know how she snuck through.
早安  长官
Morning, Sir.
别去 别再折腾了 莎伦  这可是杜亚拉
Don't. Don't even think it. Sharon, it's Dualla.
杜亚拉在下面    她有丈夫
Dualla went down there. She has a husband.
不错 他出去巡逻了
Yeah, and he's out flying CAP.
她不会有事的 她吃了药 就会没事的
She'll be fine. She'll take her meds. She'll be fine.
你知道船上的人都在说什么吗?  你和那些撒纪特恩人
You know what's all over the ship? You and the Sagittarons.
你对他们有求必应
How you might actually be listening to them.
那是我的工作
That's my job.
他们要死了 是因为他们拒绝服药
They're dying because they're refusing medication, Karl.
你想让我视而不见吗?  是吗?
You want me to look the other way. Is that it? Is that it?
我们的女儿没事 这才是最重要的?      不是
Our daughter's fine. That's all that matters? No!
要不然就是 只要大家都讨厌撒纪特恩人
Or is it because as long as everyone hates the Sagittarons,
他们就会暂时忘记你是赛昂人?
they'll forget you're a Cylon for five minutes.
你他妈的给我少说两句
You shut the frak up.
对 我是想让你别去管
Yeah. I want you to look the other way.
我每天都在这艘船上努力拼搏 想让大家接受我
I have to fight every single day on this ship to be accepted.
这件事与你无关 知道吗?
This has nothing to do with you! Okay?
你以为我是那种人?  我成了那种人吗?
You think that's who I am? That's what I've become?
"娶了一个赛昂人的男人" 就算是我的代名词?
That's my defining characteristic? The guy married to a Cylon?
这家伙绝非善类
This guy's dirty.
我看他是个骗子 他在害人
I think he's a liar and I think he's killing people
因为他是一个种族主义的混蛋
because he's a racist son of a bitch.
让开  让开!
Make a hole! Get out of the way!
让开  让开
Get out of the way! Get out of the way!
小杜?  小杜?
Dee? Dee?
杜亚拉?
Dualla?
不 不  不  不
No. No, no, no, no!
杜亚拉
Dualla. Hey!
你怎么会在这里?
Hey. What are you doing down here?
我让罗伯特医生给我开了一些药 结果我就晕了过去
Dr. Robert, he gave me something that kicked the frak out of me.
李在哪?      我们这就去见他 来吧
Where's Lee? We're gonna go see him. Come on.
带你去见科特尔
Come on. Gotta take you to Cottle.
不用   不  来吧
No. Yeah, yeah, yeah. Come on.
他是个"僵尸手"      我知道  来吧
He's got hands of stone. I know. I know. Come on.
你想干什么?
Hey. What the hell are you doing here?
我要带她走
She's coming with me.
不行 以她的状态哪都去不了
No, she's not. She's in no condition to go anywhere.
我要带她到科特尔那里确诊
I'm taking her to Cottle, just to be sure.
确诊是什么意思?  你给我出去!
What do you mean, be... Hey, hey! Get the hell out of here!
医生  你他妈快给我让道!
Get the frak out of my way, Doctor! Now!
来  走吧
Come on, honey. Come on. No.
警卫!
Security!
阿格森疯了 他要伤害我的病人
Agathon, he's lost it. I don't know. He's hurting one of my patients.
他在毒害她 我要带她去见科特尔
He poisoned her. I'm taking her to Cottle.
叫副官来
ROBERT: Get the XO.
别管我
DUALLA: Leave me alone.
长官  别让科特尔来
Sir. No. Not Cottle.
别管我
Please just leave me alone! No.
上尉  出了什么事?    别管我
Captain, what's going on, sir? Leave me alone.
上尉!  我想睡觉
Captain! I wanna sleep.
别  别睡  我们得继续走
No, no, no, Dee. Come on, we gotta go.
上尉 她不想走    我们得走
Captain, she doesn't want to go. We gotta go.
长官  她说她不想走      把你的手拿开  中士!
Sir! She says she doesn't want to go! Get your hand off me, Sergeant!
站住 长官
You stand down, sir!
把你的手拿开!
Get your frakking hands off me!
把枪给我拿开
Get your gun out of my face!
冷静
Cool it!
我不知道你在搞什么鬼 或是要向谁炫耀什么
I don't know what kind of a crusade you're on or who you're trying to impress,
但你这么做根本没用
but it seriously is not working.
你在害人 我知道你在害人!
You're killing them, Robert. I know you're doing it.
退后
Stand down!
少
Saul.
你和我说过他人很怪 可你没说他是个危险
You told me he was a flake. You didn't tell me he was dangerous!
妈的  闭嘴!
Shut the frak up!
她的情况怎么样?
How is she?
她服用了镇静剂 但无大碍
She's been sedated. But she's okay.
你不信他的那套鬼话吧?
Wait a minute, wait a minute. You don't believe him, do you?
他的妄想症很严重 需要去看医生
He's seriously delusional. He needs help.
对 还不如直接杀了他
Yeah. And we should have given it to him.
医生
HELO: Doc?
直到几个小时前  我才去核查威利的血样
I didn't check Willie's blood until a couple of hours ago.
在此之前我累得要命 我也承认撒纪特恩人让我心烦
I was exhausted, and I'll admit the Sagittarons annoy the hell out of me.
我又不想和我同事对着干
And I didn't want to go against my colleague.
但那些病历的事 西洛说得对
But you were right about their records, Helo.
金女士儿子的体内  根本没有贝他霉素
There was no bittamusin in the King boy's body.
他死了是因为来得太晚了    不  才不是
He died because it was too late. No, he didn't.
他的死因是急性细胞损伤
He died of acute cell destruction.
他被注射了有毒的二磷酸盐
He was injected with a toxic bisphosphonate.
你的诊断明显有误
Now, obviously, you got a wrong reading here.
我不知道这些人还有…    没有!
Now I don't know what else these people... No!
那个老头  巴克明斯特先生的死因也是如此
The old man, Mr. Buckminster, died of the same thing.
他的体内也没有贝他霉素
There was no bittamusin in his system.
是你害死了他们  你他妈的死变态
You killed them, you sick frak.
你应该跪下来  感谢我救了你的女儿
You ought to be on your knees, thanking me for saving your daughter's life,
感谢我还留着药  来为她治病
for having the meds to cure her of her illness.
你也清楚  这种病的晚期有多痛苦
Now you know how painful this disease is at the end.
如果他们不需要我们的帮助
And they don't want our help.
为什么我们还要 浪费时间  空间和药物
Now, why waste time and meds and space on them
而不把这些资源给那些真正需要它们的人?
when all of those resources could go to those who really deserve it?
当药物不够用的时候 又该给谁
Who gets the medication when there's not enough to go around?
撒纪特恩人连对自己的种族
A Sagittaron who won't even raise a finger
或一名驾驶员都不愿出手相助
to save his own race, or a Viper pilot?
那"救死扶伤"又是怎么回事  医生?
What the hell happened to "Do no harm," Doctor?
我之所以卷了进来  是因为必须有人敢下狠心
Look, I intervened because someone has to make the tough choices here.
但这已经不重要了
But it doesn't matter.
不重要了 因为你看看他们  反正他们都会毁了自己
It doesn't matter because, look at them, they're gonna destroy themselves anyway.
看看他们  看看他们站在那里
I mean, look at them. Look at them out there.
他们像是待宰的羔羊
They're like worms crawling on a hot rock.
还记得你以前常说什么吗  少?
Remember what you used to say, Saul?
除了赛昂人 还有比撒纪特恩人更让你厌恶的东西吗?
Aside from a Cylon, is there anything that you hate more than a Sagittaron?
让我告诉你我讨厌什么  麦克  犯错误
I'll tell you what I hate, Mike. Being wrong.
阿格森上尉   是 长官
Captain Agathon. Sir.
把这狗娘养的给我逮起来 如果有必要 就给他戴上嚼子
Arrest this son of a bitch. Gag him if you have to.
乐意至致  长官
My pleasure, sir.
我没害她
I didn't harm her.
对  她是一个好人
Right. She's one of the good ones.
长官 你找我?
Sir. You wanted to see me?
对  上尉  请坐
Yes, Captain. Please, sit down.
仇恨以及对仇恨的置若罔闻
There's hate and there's allowing hate.
其实是同一枚硬币的正反两面
Two sides of the same coin, really.
两者都负有责任
We're guilty of both.
我们在某处迷失了
Somewhere we got lost.
只留你在荒原中独自前行
You being the lone voice in the wilderness,
而我们却还要向前走一段时间
we were bound to stay that way for a while.
这是我的战舰
This is my ship.
我应该向你道歉
And I owe you an apology.
没必要这么做  长官
That's not necessary, sir.
纵然如此...
All the same,
你依旧雄姿英发
you still have it.
没事了  上尉
That'll be all, Captain.